[
    [
        {
            "question":"A sells a watch to B at a profit of 33% and B sells it to C at a loss of 20%. If C pays ‚Çπ532, then what was the cost price for A?",
            "options":[500,800,600,400],
            "answer":500,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"B purchased 15 kg apples at the rate of ‚Çπ180 per kg from a wholesaler who uses a weight of 950 grams for the kg weight. B sold all these apples at ‚Çπ180 per kg but used a weight of 750 grams for the kg weight. Find the percentage profit earned by B in the transaction (correct to 2 places of decimal).",
            "options":[22.55,33.33,25.75,26.67],
            "answer":26.67,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Aditya sold article X at a profit of 23% and article Y at a loss of 13%. He earned a profit of ‚Çπ180 in the entire transaction. If article X costs ‚Çπ90 less than article Y, then what is the price of article Y (in ‚Çπ )?",
            "options":[2007,2050,2100,2020],
            "answer":2007,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Arun brought 50 kg of rice at a discount of 15% on the marked price. For purchasing bulk quantity, he was given 5 kg of wheat (the marked price of which was 60% the marked price of rice) free of cost. Had the retailer sold both items at their marked price to his other customers, then approximately what would be the profit percentage that the shopkeeper could earn ?",
            "options":[24.7,25.2,22.8,23.5],
            "answer":24.7,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A fruit seller buys 480 bananas for ‚Çπ1,200. Some of these bananas are rotten and hence, they are thrown away. He sells the remaining bananas at ‚Çπ3.5 each and makes a profit of ‚Çπ396. What is the percentage of bananas thrown away? ",
            "options":[6,4.5,5,4],
            "answer":5,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A tailor buys lining clothes from a wholesale merchant and cheats him by using a measurement tape which is 5 cm longer than the normal tape. The tailor offers the customers at cost price while stitching different garments and uses measurements tape which is 5 cm shorter than the normal tape. The gain percent is:",
            "options":[15,"260/25",10,"200/19"],
            "answer":"200/19",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Rini has mixed two colours 'ùê∂ 1' and 'ùê∂ 2' in the ratio 2 : 3. If the rate of the colour 'ùê∂ 1' is ‚Çπ500 per unit and she is selling the mixture of the two colours at ‚Çπ650 per unit at breakeven price, then what is the rate (in ‚Çπ) per unit of the second colour, that is, 'ùê∂ 2'?",
            "options":[750,725,760,765],
            "answer":750,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper purchased 1600 mangos at the rate of ‚Çπ120 per dozen. Out of these, he sold 900 mangoes at ‚Çπ15 per mango and the remaining mangoes at ‚Çπ14 per mango. His gain percentage is:",
            "options":[45.625,38.265,35.625,48.765],
            "answer":45.625,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper bought a certain number of apples for Rs.3,600. He sold one - fifth of them at a loss of 10%, one-fourth of the remaining apples at a loss of 5%, and two-third of the rest at a profit of 15%. At what price (in Rs.) should he sell the remaining apples to earn a profit of 27% overall?",
            "options":[1548,1584,1845,1864],
            "answer":1584,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A retailer announces a discount of 30% for selling an air-conditioner marked at ‚Çπ92,000. The cost price of the air-conditioner is 70% below the marked price. He offers a further discount of 20% if the buyer presents his membership card of the retailer's store. The profit of the retailer with the membership card scheme is what percentage of the profit of the retailer without the membership card scheme?",
            "options":[62,65,70,74],
            "answer":65,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper is incurring a loss of cost price of 4 pens while selling 20 pens to Ajay. If the shopkeeper had purchased 20 pens at 10% less price and had sold 20 pens to Ajay at 25% more than the selling price, then how much percentage would he have gained (rounded off to 1 decimal place)?",
            "options":[8,11.1,10,12.5],
            "answer":11.1,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Ten refrigerators and four mobile phones together cost ‚Çπ2,10,000 while six refrigerators and two mobile phones together cost ‚Çπ1,22,000. The cost (in ‚Çπ) of one refrigerator and two mobile phones is:",
            "options":[37000,35200,34500,36000],
            "answer":37000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Mukesh sells two shirts. The cost price of the first shirt is equal to the selling price of the second shirt. The first shirt is sold at a profit of 20% and the second shirt is sold at a loss of 20%. What is the ratio of the selling price of the first shirt to the cost price of the second shirt?",
            "options":["18:25","97:100","24:25","27:50"],
            "answer":"24:25",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Akshay has 30 articles, each having the same cost price. He marked the price of each article at 30% above its cost price. He sold 15 of the articles at a discount of 20% each and the remaining 15 articles at a discount of 10% each, thereby gaining a total profit of ‚Çπ630. What was the cost price of each article?",
            "options":[240,180,280,200],
            "answer":200,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A dishonest dealer is selling sugar at Rs. 40 per kg and pretending that he is selling it at a loss of Rs. 5 per kg but he actually gives 800g instead of 1 kg, using a faulty weight. What is his actual profit or loss percent?",
            "options":["Gain 11%","Gain 100/9%","Loss 91/9%","Loss 82/9%"],
            "answer":"Gain 100/9%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"A woman sold her earphone for Rs.2,000 and got a percentage profit equal to the numerical value of cost price. The cost price of the earphone is:",
            "options":[500,200,600,400],
            "answer":400,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A manufacturer sells an item to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 11%. The wholesaler sells the same to a retailer at a profit of 15%. The retailer in turn sells it to a customer for ‚Çπ17,045, thereby earning a profit of 19%. The cost price of the manufacturer is (consider integral part only) :",
            "options":[13520,15020,10200,11220],
            "answer":11220,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Aditya sells two wrist watches from his personal collection for ‚Çπ12,600 each. On the first watch he gains 26% and on the second he loses 10%. Find the overall profit percentage?",
            "options":[16,15,5,12],
            "answer":5,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sushant buys goods worth Rs.8000. He gets a discount of 10% on that article. After getting the exemption, he pays tax at the rate of 7.5%. Find the amount he will have to pay for this goods received at his residence, if the shopkeeper charges Rs.200 for home delivery",
            "options":[7940,8155,9660,6851],
            "answer":7940,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The difference between the selling prices of some apples, if sold for ‚Çπ12 per apple instead of ‚Çπ9 per apple, is ‚Çπ870. If total cost price of all the apples is ‚Çπ2,320, then find the selling price of one apple if the profit earned is 25%",
            "options":[15,10,12,8],
            "answer":10,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Joseph bought two woollen jackets for Rs. 2100 and Rs. 3150 respectively. By selling the first at a gain of k% and the second at a loss of k%, he found the selling price of both is the same. What is the value of k?",
            "options":[20,22.64,15,25],
            "answer":20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"When an article is sold for Rs.720, there is a profit of x%. When the same article is sold for Rs.750, profit is (x + 5) %. What is the value of x ?",
            "options":[20,18,25,1],
            "answer":20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"35% of goods were sold at a profit of 65%, while the remaining were sold at x% loss. If the overall loss is 12%, then what is the value of x? (correct to one decimal place)",
            "options":[51.8,50.6,53.5,52.4],
            "answer":53.5,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"How many kg of salt costing Rs. 28 per kg must be mixed with 6.6 kg of salt costing Rs. 16 per kg, so that selling the mixture at Rs. 29.90, there is a gain of 15%?",
            "options":[33,31,35,32],
            "answer":33,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"By selling two articles for Rs 800, a person gains the cost price of three articles. The profit percent is:",
            "options":[125,140,120,150],
            "answer":150,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"An article is sold at a certain price. If it is sold at 33 1/3 % of this price, there is a loss of 33 1/3 %. What is the percentage profit when it is sold at 60% of the original selling price?",
            "options":[20,30,100,51],
            "answer":20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sujata sold 25 articles for Rs. 1250 and she incurred a loss of 10%. How many articles should she sell for Rs. 2600 so that she can get a profit of 17% ?",
            "options":[26,40,25,42],
            "answer":40,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The sum of cost prices of A and B is Rs. 1200. The sum of the selling prices of A and B is Rs. 1390. If the profit of 10% and 20% is obtained on A and B respectively, then find the ratio between the cost prices of A and B",
            "options":["5:7","5:9","7:13","6:11"],
            "answer":"5:7",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper earns the same percent of profit as well as loss by selling two similar pieces of furniture for Rs 18000 and Rs 10000, respectively. At what price should he sell it to earn a profit of 50%?",
            "options":[21000,20250,21750,19500],
            "answer":21000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper gains 400% on a transaction. If the cost increases by 100% and there is no change in the selling price, then find the ratio between new profit and selling price.",
            "options":["1:3","2:5","3:5","1:2"],
            "answer":"3:5",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"Parikh sold his pen at a profit of Rs 11. He calculated the profit percentage on selling price and found it to be 25%. the cost price (in Rs) of the pen is:",
            "options":[33,24,36,44],
            "answer":33,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"If 20% of the goods are sold at 50% profit, 40% of the goods at 20% loss, 20% of the goods at 5% loss and the remaining at no loss or no profit, then the overall profit percentage is:",
            "options":[5,8,4,1],
            "answer":1,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Two articles were sold for Rs 2400 each by a shopkeeper. The shopkeeper incurred no profit and no loss on the whole transaction. If one of the two articles sold at a profit of 20%, then what was the loss incurred on the other article?",
            "options":[600,400,380,240],
            "answer":400,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"P sold an article to Q at a profit of 20%. Q sold the same article to R at a loss of 25%. R sold the same article to T at a profit of 50%. If P bought the article at Rs 100, then at what price did T buy that article? ",
            "options":[145,125,115,135],
            "answer":135,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A sold an article on 15% profit for Rs. 1495. He purchased another article whose cost price was equal to that of the first article. He sold this new article at 10% profit. What is the total profit of A ?",
            "options":[325,450,375,425],
            "answer":325,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The cost prices of article A and article B are Rs. 1200 and Rs. 1600 respectively. The selling price of article A is Rs. 1380 and the total profit after selling both the articles is 25%. What is the profit percentage on the article B ?",
            "options":[27.5,32.5,29.5,35.5],
            "answer":32.5,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"An article is sold for Rs 6500 so as to earn a profit of 4%. A second article whose cost price is Rs 3750, is sold at a loss of 4%. What is the overall gain or loss percent in the whole transaction?",
            "options":["Gain 45%","Loss 1%","Loss 4%","Gain 1%"],
            "answer":"Gain 1%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A man bought three articles for Rs 3,000 each. He sold the articles respectively at 10% profit, 5% profit and 15% loss. The total percentage profit/loss he earned is:",
            "options":["10% Loss","5% Loss","5% Profit","no profit no loss"],
            "answer":"no profit no loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Two articles are sold for Rs.9,720 each. On one, the seller gains 8% and on the other, he loses 10%. What is his overall gain or loss?",
            "options":["380 gain","380 loss","360 loss","360 gain"],
            "answer":"360 loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A person sells an article at a profit of 12%. If he had purchased it for 12% less and sold it for Rs.9 less, he would have gained 27%. What is the original cost price of the article?",
            "options":[4250,4000,4500,3750],
            "answer":3750,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sushma bought 6 tables and 12 chairs for Rs.12000. She sold the tables at a profit of 15% and the chairs at a loss of 10%. If her total gain was 300, then the total cost of the tables was:",
            "options":[6000,5000,5400,4800],
            "answer":6000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Abhi bought two articles for Rs.624. He sold one at a loss of 14% and the other at a profit of 14%. If the selling price of both the articles is equal, then the difference between their cost prices (in Rs) is:",
            "options":[89.64,87.36,89.68,88.84],
            "answer":87.36,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The marked price of an article is Rs.315. It is sold for Rs. 288. If there is a loss of 4%, then by what percent above the cost is the article marked?",
            "options":[5,8,7.5,5.5],
            "answer":5,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A person sold an article at a loss of 15%. Had he sold it for Rs. 30.60 more, he would have gained 9%. To gain 10%, he should have sold it for:",
            "options":[140.25,132,130,128.40],
            "answer":140.25,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A bought 38 kg. Rice at Rs. 54.50/kg, 45 Kg rice at Rs. 62/kg, and 55 kg rice at Rs. 48/kg . He sold the mixture at Rs. 65/kg. His loss or profit percentage is:",
            "options":["loss 1.04","loss 1.7","profit 19.6","profit 16.8"],
            "answer":"profit 19.6",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"Three partners A, B and C share profit and losses in the ratio 3:4:7 If the profit for the year before charging 30% tax is Rs. 1,10,166 What is B‚Äôs share of profit after tax?",
            "options":[9442.80,31476,22033.20,24673.10],
            "answer":22033.20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A cyclist sells 3 cycles at the loss of Rs. 129 per bicycle and 12 cycles on the profit of 516 per cycle. If the total profit on all the bicycles sold is 15%, then what will be the cost per cycle?",
            "options":[2960,3870,2580,4440],
            "answer":2580,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A manufacturer sells the product to a wholesaler at 6% profit, the wholesaler sells the product to a retailer at 8% profit and the retailer sells the product to his customer at 10% profit. The price paid by the customer is Rs 31,482. The cost of the product to the manufacturer is:",
            "options":[28306,26524,25000,26980],
            "answer":25000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The cost of 4 chairs and 3 tables is ‚Çπ2,100 and the cost of 5 chairs and 2 tables is ‚Çπ1,750. Find the cost ( in ‚Çπ) of a chair",
            "options":[150,130,140,125],
            "answer":150,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper sold his goods at half the list price and thus lost 17%. If he had sold on the listed price, then his gain percentage would be:",
            "options":[17,41,83,66],
            "answer":66,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sohan sells sugar at the cost price but uses false weights thus gaining 28% profit. How many grams of sugar is he giving for 3.2 kg sugar?",
            "options":[1500,1900,2200,2500],
            "answer":2500,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Two friends A and B started a business by investing ‚Çπ1,50,000 and ‚Çπ2,50,000, respectively. They agreed to distribute their earnings in the same ratio of their investments. After an year, the profit earned was ‚Çπ6,00,000. Each of them added ‚Çπ50,000 to their respective profits and invested in a different project. If this project gave an yield of ‚Çπ4,20,000, then A‚Äôs share in the profit is:",
            "options":[235000,165000,197000,184000],
            "answer":165000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The first shirt is sold at twice the selling price of the second shirt. The first shirt is sold at 8% profit and the second shirt is sold at a 3% loss. What is the overall percentage profit on the shirts (Rounded off to two decimal places)?",
            "options":[4.60,4.07,3.86,4.86],
            "answer":4.07,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sukhvir purchased some perishable items for sale but 30% of  those items could not be sold and went bad. However, Sukhvir managed to sell the rest of the items at a price that helped him earn an overall profit of 19%. At what percentage above the cost price of each item purchased by Sukhvir did he sell each of the items that did not go bad?",
            "options":[49,70,75,63],
            "answer":70,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"If the difference between the selling prices of an article at profits of 10% and 7% is ‚Çπ6, then the cost price (in ‚Çπ) of the article is",
            "options":[175,150,200,100],
            "answer":200,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Mayur sold a watch at a profit of 7%. If he had sold it for ‚Çπ1,329 more, he would have gained 57%. Find the cost price (in ‚Çπ) of the watch.",
            "options":[2856,2658,2580,2420],
            "answer":2658,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"After deducing a commission of 20%, a DVD set costs ‚Çπ9,080. Its marked price is:",
            "options":[11350,10100,10000,11200],
            "answer":11350,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A dealer sells his goods at 10% loss on the cost price but uses 25% less weight. What is his profit percentage ?",
            "options":[20,35,25,15],
            "answer":20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Avi sold a house to Bhargav at a gain of 10% and Bhargav sold it to Chetan at a gain of 20%. If Chetan paid ‚Çπ2,64,00,000 for it, then at what price must Avi have purchased it ?",
            "options":[25000000,17500000,23000000,20000000],
            "answer":20000000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A vendor marked the selling price of a table at ‚Çπ5,670 after adding 35% profit to its cost price. Since the sale was very low at this price level, he decided to sell the table with 12% profit. Find the new selling price (in ‚Çπ)",
            "options":[4750,4608,4810,4704],
            "answer":4704,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"The price of a land passing through three hands rises on the whole by 65%. The first and second sellers earned 20% and 25% profit, respectively. Find the profit percentage earned by the third seller.",
            "options":[15,20,10,25],
            "answer":10,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"By selling 42 m of cloth, Vijay gains the selling price of 7 m of cloth. Find the profit percentage.",
            "options":[20,30,25,15],
            "answer":20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper increases the cost price of an item by 50% and offers a discount of 40% on this marked price. What is his loss percentage ?",
            "options":[15,10,5,20],
            "answer":10,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Mihir buys a book for ‚Çπ625. However, because of certain urgency, he sells it for ‚Çπ550. Find his loss percentage.",
            "options":[10,13,14,15],
            "answer":12,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Mahesh agreed to sell rice with 24% loss, as the rice got rotten. However, he cheated customers and gave only 19 gm of rice in place of 50 gm of rice. What is the percentage of his profit or loss ?",
            "options":["100% loss","100% profit","99.99% loss","99.99% profit"],
            "answer":"100% profit",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"By selling a table for ‚Çπ1,596, Aarav loses 24%. At what price (in ‚Çπ) should he sell it to gain 24%?",
            "options":[2604,1979,3196,3024],
            "answer":2604,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Arbind has 650 kg of wheat. A part of which he sells at 9% profit and the rest at 19% profit to get 15% profit on the whole. What is the quantity (in kg) of wheat sold by Arbind at 9% profit?",
            "options":[260,390,195,455],
            "answer":260,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A person sold two cars for ‚Çπ60,000 each. On one, he gained 20% while on the other he lost 20%. Find the percentage of his gain or losses",
            "options":["no profit no loss","loss 4%","loss 2%","gain 4%"],
            "answer":"loss 4%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper sells sugar at ‚Çπ40 per kg, which he purchased at ‚Çπ36 per kg. His weighing machine is faulty and it weighs only 800 gm while selling. His percentage profit (correct to 2 decimal places) is:",
            "options":[40,37.58,38.89,39.28],
            "answer":38.89,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Ankita sold three toys. The first toy was sold for ‚Çπ1,500 at a profit of 25%; the second toy was sold for ‚Çπ2,800 at a loss of 50% and the third toy was sold for ‚Çπ3,500 at a profit of 25%. Find her total profit or loss percentage",
            "options":["15.25% profit","18.75% profit","18.75% loss","15.25% loss"],
            "answer":"18.75% loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Raju sold an article to Ravi at 10% gain. Ravi sold the article to Ramu at a loss of 10%. If Ramu paid ‚Çπ1,485 to Ravi, find the selling price of Raju to Ravi.",
            "options":[1200,1500,1650,1600],
            "answer":1650,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Samridhi sold a gold ring at a loss of 26%. If the cost price of the gold ring is ‚Çπ38,500, what is the selling price of the gold ring?",
            "options":[28490,30500,29590,38600],
            "answer":28490,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Shobha purchased a small plot in a residential area for ‚Çπ6,00,000 and sold it to Lakshita at a profit of 20%. Lakshita, in turn, sold it to Dinesh at a loss of 10%. How much did Dinesh pay for the plot ?",
            "options":[640000,648000,608000,600000],
            "answer":648000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The cost price of an article is ‚Çπ1,120. After allowing a discount of ‚Çπ205 a gain of 15% was made, then the marked price of the article is:",
            "options":[1760,1493,1350,1580],
            "answer":1493,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A manufacturer earns a profit of 10% on selling his products to a wholesale dealer. The wholesale dealer earns a profit of 15% by selling it to a retailer. The retailer, in turn, earns a profit of 25% from the customer. What is the actual cost of production of an article for which the customer pays ‚Çπ12,650 ?",
            "options":[8000,8500,9000,7000],
            "answer":8000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"By selling a TV set for ‚Çπ16,800, a salesman gains a profit of 20%. If the production cost is increased by 20%, find the new selling price of the set so as to gain 20%.",
            "options":[18160,18480,20160,20480],
            "answer":20160,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A grocer purchased 50 kg of sugar at ‚Çπ40 per kg and mixed with 70 kg of sugar at ‚Çπ30 per kg. At what rate should he sell the mixture (per kg) to gain 20%?",
            "options":[60,20,35,41],
            "answer":41,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The marked price of mustard oil is 10% more than its cost price. At what percentage less than the marked price should it be sold to have no profit and no loss?",
            "options":["102/11 %","101/11 %","100/11 %","103/11 %"],
            "answer":"100/11 %",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A store sells an item for ‚Çπ500, making a profit of 25%. Later, the store reduces the price of the item by 20% to clear out old inventory. What is the new percentage profit or loss for the store?",
            "options":["2% profit","5% profit","5% loss","no profit no loss"],
            "answer":"no profit no loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Vaishali booked a bus ticket for ‚Çπ1,260. Because of her ill health, she had to cancel the ticket. She got a refund of ‚Çπ945 in this process. What is the percentage loss that Vaishali had to face?",
            "options":[23,15,25,33],
            "answer":25,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Divya bought six candies for a rupee. How many candies for a rupee must she sell to gain 50%?",
            "options":[1,2,3,4],
            "answer":4,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"By selling 8 items, a shopkeeper gains the selling price of 2 items. The gain percentage of the shopkeeper is:",
            "options":["25%","50/3%","100/3%","30%"],
            "answer":"100/3%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Zeenat earns 20% on an investment, but she loses 10% on other investments. If the two investments are respectively in the ratio of 3 : 5, then what is the percentage gain or loss for Zeenat on the two investments taken together ?",
            "options":["1.25% gain","2.25% loss","1.25% loss","2.25% gain"],
            "answer":"1.25% gain",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The profit obtained by a vendor on selling goods at ‚Çπ3,200 is equal to the 7/5 of the profit obtained by selling the same goods at ‚Çπ3,000. What is the cost price (in ‚Çπ) of the goods?",
            "options":[2500,2700,2400,2900],
            "answer":2500,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"By selling a book at some price, Ankita gains 10%. If the book is sold at twice the price, then what will be the gain percentage for Ankita?",
            "options":[140,100,120,125],
            "answer":120,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The ratio of cost price to selling price of an article is 186 : 206. The profit per cent on it is :",
            "options":["12 50/93","12 70/93","10 70/93","10 50/93"],
            "answer":"10 70/93",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Kavita bought a table at 30% discount on its original price. She sold it with 48% increase on the price she bought it. What is the percentage difference between the new sale price and original price ? If the original price is ‚Çπ8,000, then how much extra money did Kavita get as profit ?",
            "options":["5.6% Rs.280","3.6% Rs.288","6% Rs.360","4.5% Rs.308"],
            "answer":"3.6% Rs.288",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The cost price of an item is ‚Çπ4,850. What is the profit percentage (rounded off to 1 decimal place) if it is sold at ‚Çπ6,680 ?",
            "options":[44.6,37.7,39.5,35.5],
            "answer":37.7,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A man sold his cycle at 17% loss. If he had sold it for ‚Çπ1,056 more, he would have made 5% profit. The cost price of the cycle is ",
            "options":[4700,3800,5100,4800],
            "answer":4800,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The percentage profit earned by selling an article for ‚Çπ955 is equal to the percentage loss incurred by selling the same article for ‚Çπ845. At what price should the article be sold to make a 6% profit?",
            "options":[955,954,925,1014],
            "answer":954,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"Ravi sells a laptop bag to Reeta for ‚Çπ1,920 and he sells another similar laptop bag to Vinay for ‚Çπ1,280. The percentage profit earned in selling the laptop bag to Reeta is equal to the percentage loss in selling the laptop bag to Vinay At what price (in ‚Çπ) should Ravi sell the laptop bag to make a profit of 25%?",
            "options":[1650,1600,1800,2000],
            "answer":2000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"If the manufacturer gains 10%, the wholesale dealer gains 12% and the retailer gains 15%, then find the cost production of a table, the retail price of which is ‚Çπ1,771 ",
            "options":[1150,1050,1250,1350],
            "answer":1250,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Robin purchases a fan for ‚Çπ2,000 and later sells it at a loss of 15%. At what price did he sell the fan ?",
            "options":[1900,1800,1700,2100],
            "answer":1700,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"By investing ‚Çπ12,000 in a scheme, R gets ‚Çπ15,500 back in return. What is his percentage of profit ?",
            "options":[27.19,29.17,17.92,19.17],
            "answer":29.17,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A milk vendor mixes water with milk and by selling the mixture at the cost price be gains, 16 1/4%. Find the ratio of milk to water in the mixture.",
            "options":["7:40","80:13","13:80","40:7"],
            "answer":"80:13",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A company buys raw materials for ‚Çπ10,000 and manufactures a product that costs an additional ‚Çπ5,000 in labour and overhead. The product is sold to a distributor for ‚Çπ25,000, who marks it up by 20% and sells it to a retailer. The retailer then marks it up by another 25% and sells it to the end customer. What is the overall percentage profit made by the company, distributor, and retailer combined ?",
            "options":[100,150,125,135],
            "answer":150,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Anil sells a car to Bina at a profit of 20%. Bina sells it to Karan at a profit of 25%. If Karan pays ‚Çπ2,25,000 for it, then, find the CP of the car for Anil .",
            "options":[175000,200000,150000,125000],
            "answer":150000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"By selling at a loss of 12% instead of a loss of 18% an article sells for ‚Çπ120 more. Find its CP",
            "options":[2100,2000,1500,1800],
            "answer":2000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Raman buys an article for ‚Çπ1,00,000 and sells it to Mohit for ‚Çπ1,20,000. Mohit again sells the same article to Rashmi for ‚Çπ1,00,000. What is the percentage loss faced by Mohit ?",
            "options":["50/3%","55/3%","20%","15%"],
            "answer":"50/3%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A seller marked the price of a sofa 25% more than its cost price. If he allows 12% discount on the marked price to the customer, then what is his gain percentage? If the cost price of the sofa is ‚Çπ15,000, then what is his gain money?",
            "options":["9% Rs.1480","8% Rs.1350","10% Rs.1500","9.5% Rs.1600"],
            "answer":"10% Rs.1500",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Aditya sold two bags for ‚Çπ630 each. On one bag he gains 33% and on the other he losses 33%. Find his gain or loss per cent on the whole transaction.",
            "options":["12.37% gain","10.89% gain","10.89% loss","12.37% loss"],
            "answer":"10.89% loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":" By selling a calculator for ‚Çπ1,080, there is a loss of 10%, if the article is sold for ‚Çπ1,350, the net result in the transaction is ",
            "options":["25/2% loss","12% gain","25/2% gain","12% loss"],
            "answer":"25/2% gain",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Some oranges were purchased at ‚Çπ150 per hundred and sold at ‚Çπ24 per dozen. It gave a gain of ‚Çπ1,000. How many oranges were purchased  ",
            "options":[3000,2500,1500,2000],
            "answer":2000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A medical store owner purchased medicines worth ‚Çπ18,000 from a company. He sold 2/5 part of the medicine at a 35% loss. On which gain, he should sell the rest of the medicines so that he has neither gain nor loss ?",
            "options":["23 2/3%","20 2/3%","20 1/3%","23 1/3%"],
            "answer":"23 1/3%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Ramesh purchased a bag for ‚Çπ 1,275 and sold it at a gain of 15% but calculated on the selling price. Find the selling price of the bag.",
            "options":[1325,1400,1475,1500],
            "answer":1500,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"A microwave and a dish washing machine were sold for ‚Çπ27,000 each. If the microwave was sold at a gain of 25% and the dish washing machine at a loss of 25%. What is the overall profit % or loss% on the entire transaction?",
            "options":["5.50% loss","7.75% profit","6.25% loss","8.25% profit"],
            "answer":"6.25% loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper bought an oven for ‚Çπ25,000 and sold it for ‚Çπ29,500. He spent ‚Çπ1,500 as overheads. What is his loss or gain percentage (rounded off to the nearest integer)?",
            "options":["loss by 11%","gain by 13%","loss by 13%","gain by 11%"],
            "answer":"gain by 11%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Atul sells goods to a customer at a profit of P%. If the cost price of the goods for the customer is ‚Çπ1,50,000 and Atul makes a profit of ‚Çπ30,000, then what is the value of P ?",
            "options":[22,25,20,28],
            "answer":20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A jewel was sold passing through 3 hands and on the whole, its price is raised by 80%. The first seller earns 20% profit and the second seller earns 25% profit, respectively. Find the percentage of profit earned by the third seller",
            "options":[20,10,15,5],
            "answer":20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Praveen sells a study table to Zoya at a loss of 10%, and Zoya sells the study table to Aadarsh at a profit of 25%. If Aadarsh purchased the study table for ‚Çπ2,250, then what was the cost (in ‚Çπ) of the study table for Praveen?",
            "options":[2000,2100,1800,1900],
            "answer":2000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A factory owner earns 12% on the product manufactured by him. The shopkeeper earns 10% profit on the same item. If shopkeeper sells the product for ‚Çπ98.56, then the cost price of the product for the factory owner is ‚Çπ_____.",
            "options":[88,90,84,80],
            "answer":80,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"If a loss is 1/8th of the selling price then the loss percentage is",
            "options":["11 1/9%","7 4/9%","10 1/9%","8 5/9%"],
            "answer":"11 1/9%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper marks his goods at 80% more than their cost price and allows a discount of 48% on the marked price. His loss percentage is:",
            "options":["11/5%","38/5%","32/5%","16/5%"],
            "answer":"32/5%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A dishonest shopkeeper professes to sell grains at the cost price, but he uses a weight of 920 gm for 1 kg weight. Find his gain percentage (round up to two decimal places).",
            "options":[7.90,8.70,8.50,7.80],
            "answer":8.70,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"In a showroom, the marked prices of various items are displayed in such a manner that after giving a 10% discount to the customers, the owner of the show room earns a profit of 20%. What is the ratio of the marked price and cost price of each item?",
            "options":["3:4","4:3","5:2","2:5"],
            "answer":"4:3",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A man buys a toy car for ‚Çπ225 and sells it for ‚Çπ210. Find his loss percentage (round up to two decimal places).",
            "options":[4.44,93.33,3.33,6.67],
            "answer":6.67,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A publisher supplies books to a book-seller at 20% discount on the list price of ‚Çπ1,574.80. If the book-seller sells books at the list price and if his expenses for freight etc. are ‚Çπ45.40. Determine his profit.",
            "options":[285.34,269.56,273.50,282.22],
            "answer":269.56,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Manoj marked his goods 30% above the Cost Price and gives a 12% to the discounts to the customers. The profit or loss percentage is :",
            "options":["14.8% loss","15.4% profit","14.4% profit","15% loss"],
            "answer":"14.4% profit",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper marked a product 40% above the cost price and sold the product for ‚Çπ3,780 by giving a discount of 10%. The profit percentage of the shopkeeper is :",
            "options":[30,26,42,14],
            "answer":26,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"S sells an item costing ‚Çπ37,800 to P with 8% profit. P sells it to Q with a 4% loss. At what price (in ‚Çπ) does P sell the item? (Correct to a nearest rupee)",
            "options":[39919,39119,39191,39911],
            "answer":39191,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"If a man purchases kismis at ‚Çπ320 per kg and sells it at ‚Çπ6 per 25 grams, then his profit / loss percentage is:",
            "options":["20% loss","25% loss","25% profit","20% profit"],
            "answer":"25% loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The ratio of cost price (CP) and marked price (MP) of an article is 4 : 7. A discount of 20% is given on MP and the shopkeeper made a profit of ‚Çπ80. Find the CP of the article.",
            "options":[190,170,200,180],
            "answer":200,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"In April 2019, Dinesh purchased a new car for ‚Çπ7,00,000 and sold it in April 2022 at its depreciated cost. If the rate of depreciation in the first year is 20%, 15% in the second year and 10% every year thereafter, what amount of money will Dinesh get as the selling price ?",
            "options":[428400,428600,468400,528400],
            "answer":428400,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A profit earned by selling an article for ‚Çπ1,032 is equal to the loss incurred when the same article is sold for ‚Çπ648. What should be the selling price of the article if the profit is 30% ?",
            "options":[2520,1050,1092,998],
            "answer":1092,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A trader allows a 40% discount on his goods, but he loses 30% on them. Find the percentage of the marked price above the cost prices",
            "options":["15 2/3%","15 1/3%","16 2/3%","16 1/3%"],
            "answer":"16 2/3%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The marked price of the cupboard is ‚Çπ15,750, which is 50% above its cost price. It is sold at a discount of 40%.What is the profit/loss percentage?",
            "options":["profit 10%","loss 10%","loss 20%","profit 20%"],
            "answer":"loss 10%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A vendor earns 10% on an investment but loses 10% on another investment. What will be the combined loss or gain if the two investments are in the ratio 1: 3 ?",
            "options":["4% loss","5% gain","4% gain","5% loss"],
            "answer":"5% loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Supriya made a profit of 8% by selling a t-shirt after offering a discount of 10%. If the marked price of the t-shirt is ‚Çπ1,080, then find its cost price (in ‚Çπ) for Supriya",
            "options":[920,940,880,900],
            "answer":900,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper professes to sell sugar costing ‚Çπ40/kg at ‚Çπ42/kg but gives only 550 grams sugar in place of 600 grams using faulty weighing machine. His profit percentage (correct to 2 decimal places) is",
            "options":[14.54,15.54,15.45,16.45],
            "answer":14.54,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A retailer buys 50 pens at the marked price of 44 pens. If he sells these pens at a discount of 1% on the marked price, what is the profit per cent?",
            "options":[10,12.5,12,15],
            "answer":12.5,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"If the cost price of a book is 92% of its selling price, then what is the percentage profit on the sale of the book (correct up to two decimal places)?",
            "options":[8.25,8.69,8,8.53],
            "answer":8.69,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A dealer gives a 7% discount on the marked price and gives 1 article free for buying every 25 articles and thus gains 25%. Find the percentage increase in the marked price above the cost price (round up to two decimal places).",
            "options":[39.78,37.88,1.4,38.87],
            "answer":39.78,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sukhen purchased some perishable items for sale but 15% of those items could not be sold and went bad. However, Sukhen managed to sell the rest of the items at a price that helped him eam an overall profit of 19%. At what percentage above the cost price of each item did Sukthen sell each of the items that did NOT go bad?",
            "options":[40,42,34,36],
            "answer":40,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The marked price of a toy car is ‚Çπ600. The shopkeeper gives a discount of 4% and still makes a profit of 28%. Find the cost price of a toy car.",
            "options":[460,420,480,450],
            "answer":450,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A tradesman marks his goods at such a price that after allowing a discount of 31%, he makes a profit of 15%. What is the marked price of an article whose cost price is ‚Çπ3,420?",
            "options":[5700,5200,5475,5550],
            "answer":5700,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"An item is sold for ‚Çπ2,744 and the seller earns 12% profit. What should be the selling price (in ‚Çπ ) to earn only 5% profit?",
            "options":[2572.50,2725.50,2527.50,2275.50],
            "answer":2572.50,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The selling price of 34 articles is equal to the cost price of 38 articles. What is the gain percentage?",
            "options":["7 6/17%","10 3/17%","11 13/17%","9 8/17%"],
            "answer":"11 13/17%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A renowned brand marked its goods at 40% above the cost price but allows a discount of 7.5% for UPI payments to the customers. What actual profit is made on a shirt, if a customer pays ‚Çπ1,813 to buy it using UPI ?",
            "options":[413,348,378,393],
            "answer":413,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The marked price of a T-shirt is ‚Çπ560. The shopkeeper Krishna allows a discount of 16% and gains 12%. What would be the gain of Krishna if no discount is allowed ?",
            "options":["16 2/3%","31 1/9%","33 1/3%","11 1/9%"],
            "answer":"33 1/3%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A person purchased ten boxes of grapes at a cost of ‚Çπ2,000 per box. Each box contained 20 kgs of grapes. He sold each box at the rate of ‚Çπ 2,500 per box. But on the whole 10 kgs of grapes were damaged. Further he paid ‚Çπ1,000 as transport charges. Find his gain or loss",
            "options":["gain 2050","loss 1000","gain 2750","loss 1500"],
            "answer":"gain 2750",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Pawan purchases 70 articles for ‚Çπ16,875 and sells them at a loss equal to the selling price of 5 articles. What will be the selling price of one article?",
            "options":[220,230,235,225],
            "answer":225,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Arun sold his goods at a loss of 10%. If the selling price of the goods had been increased by ‚Çπ270, there would have been a gain of 8%. What was the cost price (in‚Çπ) of the goods for Arun?",
            "options":[1800,1150,1650,1500],
            "answer":1500,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"At how much per cent above the cost price should a trader mark his goods so that after allowing a discount of 25%, he still gains 5%?",
            "options":[35,32,50,40],
            "answer":40,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper sells a table at 25% discount on the marked price and earns a profit of 70%. If he sells the same table at 50% discount, then his new profit percentage will be:",
            "options":["11 1/3%","12 1/2%","13 1/3%","13 1/2%"],
            "answer":"13 1/3%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A trader sells two LED sets at the same price. There is a gain of 20% on one LED and 20 % loss on the second LED. Which of the following statements is true ?",
            "options":["4% profit","profit 2%","no profit no loss","4% loss"],
            "answer":"4% loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Shyam purchased a packet of 16 pens and got 4 pens free with it. He marked the price 20% more than the CP. If he did not allow any discount and sold all the 20 pens at this price, then what was his profit percentage?",
            "options":[40,50,36,48],
            "answer":50,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper sells a table at a discount of 25% on the marked price and earns a profit of 80%. If he sells the same table at a 40% discount, then his new profit is ",
            "options":[31,44,33,41],
            "answer":44,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"By selling a watch for ‚Çπ1,600, a person gets profit that is equal to the loss of selling the same watch for ‚Çπ1,400. If the person wants to get a profit of 20%, at what price should he sell the watch?",
            "options":[1800,1700,1850,1750],
            "answer":1800,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The marked price of an item is 25% more than that of its cost price. If a discount of 10% is given on the marked price,then the gain percentage is:",
            "options":["21/2%","19/2%","27/2%","25/2%"],
            "answer":"25/2%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A tradesman marks his goods 25% above the cost price and allows his customers a discount of 12% on their bill. How much % profit tradesman realizes ?",
            "options":[13,11,12,10],
            "answer":10,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"A man sells a good at 5% profit. If he had sold it at a 10% profit, he would have received ‚Çπ175 more. What is the selling price of the good ?",
            "options":[3750,3850,3675,3500],
            "answer":3675,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The cost price of 240 articles is the same as the selling price of x articles. If profit is 20%, find the value of x.",
            "options":[200,21,180,240],
            "answer":200,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The marked price of a school bag was ‚Çπ 550. This price was 10% above the cost price. It was sold at a discount of 10% on the marked price. Find the gain or loss percentage.",
            "options":["loss 1%","loss 0.1%","gain 0.1%","gain 1%"],
            "answer":"loss 1%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The marked price of 85 items was equal to the cost price of 153 items. The selling price of 104 items was equal to the marked price of 65 items. Calculate the percentage profit from the sale of each item.",
            "options":[12.5,12.35,15,12.25],
            "answer":12.5,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A man buys an article for ‚Çπ80 and marks it at ‚Çπ125. He then allows a discount of 40%. What is his percentage of loss or gain?",
            "options":["12% gain","10% gain","6.25%  loss","12% loss"],
            "answer":"6.25% loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A man sells rice at 8% profit and uses weight 25% less than the actual measure. What is his percentage profit?",
            "options":[44,41,23,36],
            "answer":44,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A person sold two items selling each for ‚Çπ42,600. On the first item, he made a loss of 25%, while on the second, he gained 20%. Find his overall percentage gain or loss, giving your answer correct to one place of decimal",
            "options":["7.7% loss","7.7% gain","8.3% gain","8.2% loss"],
            "answer":"7.7% loss",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A 45% profit is made when a discount of 45% is given on the marked price of an item. If the discount on the marked price of the same item is 50%, then the profit will be:",
            "options":["31 9/11%","33 2/11%","30 7/11%","31 7/11%"],
            "answer":"31 9/11%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper earns a profit of 20% after offering a discount of 10% on the marked price of an electric mixer. What is the cost price (in ‚Çπ) of the electric mixer having marked price ‚Çπ 6,500?",
            "options":[4900,4825,4850,4875],
            "answer":4875,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A trader allows a discount of 5% for cash payment. What percentage above the cost price must he mark his goods to make a profit of 14% ?",
            "options":[30,40,50,20],
            "answer":20,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Deepak starts a business with a capital of ‚Çπ1,60,000. He incurs a loss of 10% during the first year. But he makes a profit of 5% during the second year on his remaining investment. Finally, he makes a profit of 25% on his new capital during the third year. Find his total profit at the end of three years.",
            "options":[29500,29000,28000,28500],
            "answer":29000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A manufacturer marked an item at ‚Çπ75 and sold it allowing a 14% discount. If his profit was 29%, then the cost price (in ‚Çπ) of the item was",
            "options":[64,57,45,50],
            "answer":50,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A sells a television to B for ‚Çπ4,860, thereby losing 19%. B sells it to C at a price which would have given A a 17% profit. Find the gain of B.",
            "options":[4160,2160,3160,1160],
            "answer":2160,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"The cost price of an article is 72% of the marked price. The profit percentage after allowing a discount of 6% on the marked price is (rounded off to 2 decimal places) ",
            "options":[32.50,28.23,30.56,35.65],
            "answer":30.56,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper does a faulty weighing of an item of 930 gram instead of 1 kg and sells it at its cost price. Find his profit percentage on selling 15 kg of the item.",
            "options":["8 79/93%","5 21/93%","7 49/93%","6 19/93%"],
            "answer":"7 49/93%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"Upon selling an article at of 3/7 the marked price, a loss of 30% is incurred. What is the ratio between the marked price and the cost price of the article?",
            "options":["48:60","49:30","25:37","50:80"],
            "answer":"49:30",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper publishes a list of prices which are 60% above the CP. He proposes to give 20% discount. How much profit does he really make?",
            "options":[35,22,18,28],
            "answer":28,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Ranjeet buys 1 kg potato for ‚Çπ20 and sells it for ‚Çπ25. He also uses a weight of 800 gm in place of 1 kg. What is the Ranjeet‚Äôs actual profit percentage on the sale of 1 kg potato?",
            "options":[56.75,56.25,55.75,57.25],
            "answer":56.25,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A dealer offers a discount of 10% on the marked price of an article and still makes a profit of 20%. If the cost price of the article is ‚Çπ540, then find the marked price (in ‚Çπ) of the articles",
            "options":[810,750,720,690],
            "answer":720,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A discount of 20% is given on the marked price of a cycle, and still there is a profit of 20%. If the profit is ‚Çπ800, find the marked price of the cycle.",
            "options":[4000,58000,48000,6000],
            "answer":6000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"If oranges are bought at 11 for ‚Çπ 10 and sold at 10 for ‚Çπ11, what is the gain or loss percentage?",
            "options":["gain 11%","loss 11%","loss 21%","gain 21%"],
            "answer":"gain 21%",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sourabh purchased an article for ‚Çπ48,000 and sold it at a loss of 12%. With that amount, she purchased another item and sold it at a gain of 20%. What is the overall gain of loss in ‚Çπ?",
            "options":["2688 loss","14208 loss","14208 gain","2688 gain"],
            "answer":"2688 gain",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A seller sold a bag at a profit of 12%. If he had sold it for ‚Çπ900 more, he would have gained 27%. What is the CP of the bag ?",
            "options":[6000,6500,5560,7000],
            "answer":6000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Shailja allows a discount of 10% to her customer and still gains 20% on the sale of a cosmetic product. What is the marked price (in ‚Çπ) of the cosmetic product having a cost price ‚Çπ450 ?",
            "options":[580,560,600,540],
            "answer":600,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A person bought two goods for ‚Çπ19,500. He sold one at a loss of 20% and the other at a profit of 15%. If the selling price of each goods is the same, find the cost price of goods sold at profit.",
            "options":[11475,11500,9750,8000],
            "answer":8000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"Akash sold a motorcycle to Navin at a profit of 10%. Navin sold it to Vinay at a profit of 20%. Vinay sold it to Vishal at a loss of 5%. If Vishal paid ‚Çπ62,700 for the motorcycle, then what was the cost of the motorcycle (in ‚Çπ) for Akash?",
            "options":[48000,48500,52500,50000],
            "answer":50000,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper uses 940 gm weight in place of one kg weight. He sells it at 4% profit. What will be the actual profit percentage? (rounded off to two decimal places)",
            "options":[9.25,10.32,10.64,10.96],
            "answer":10.64,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A shopkeeper gains 20% in place of 16% loss if the selling price of an article is increased by ‚Çπ324. The cost price of the article is:",
            "options":[900,750,1350,60],
            "answer":900,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"If the selling price of an article is doubled, then the profit becomes four times. What was the original profit percentage?",
            "options":[75,100,50,25],
            "answer":50,
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
            "question":"A dealer marks his goods at 20% above the cost price and allows a discount of 15% on the marked price. What is his gain or loss percentage?",
            "options":["4% gain","2% loss","2% gain","4% loss"],
            "answer":"2% gain",
            "category":"Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
         "question" : "R lends some money to S on which S pays ‚Çπ17,000 more to R. S lends the same money to T, on which T pays 8.5% more to S. What should be the minimum amount (in ‚Çπ) that S must borrow so that he does not incur any loss in the process?",
         "options" : ["2,00,000","2,25,000","1,80,000","1,70,000"],
         "answer" : "2,00,000",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A seller professes to sell his fruits at cost price but still gains 5 5/19%. How much does he give for 1 kg?",
         "options" : ["905 gm","5 gm","900 gm","950 gm"],
         "answer" : "950 gm",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The cost price and selling price of rice are the same. Due to a faulty weighing machine, the seller earns a 15% profit. If Rs. x is the cost price of 1000 gm rice and the machine is changed which shows 1000 gm instead of 950 gm, what should be the selling price (in ‚Çπ) now to get the same percentage of profit?",
         "options" : ["1.0295x","1.0259x","1.0925x","1.0950x"],
         "answer" : "1.0925x",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A dishonest shopkeeper sells millet at ‚Çπ20 per kg which he has bought at ‚Çπ16 per kg and he is giving 800 gm instead of 1000 gm. Find his actual profit percentage.",
         "options" : ["52.12%","58.36%","54.25%","56.25%"],
         "answer" : "56.25%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A person marks his goods x% above the cost price and allows a discount of 12% on the marked price. If his profit is 10%, then the difference between x% and the profit percentage is:",
         "options" : ["15%","18%","13%","10%"],
         "answer" : "15%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "Mona purchased two sets of jewellery for ‚Çπ4,000 each. She sold these sets of jewellery, gaining 8% on one and loosing 6% on the other. Calculate her total loss or gain in this whole transaction",
         "options" : ["‚Çπ120 gain","‚Çπ80 gain","‚Çπ80 loss","‚Çπ120 loss"],
         "answer" : "‚Çπ80 gain",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "R's weighing machine shows 400 gm when the actual weight is 350 gm. The cost price of almonds is ‚Çπ880 per kg and packets of 200 gm are made using the faulty machine. What should be the selling price (in ‚Çπ) of each packet to get a profit of 25%?",
         "options" : ["197.50","175.50","182.50","192.50"],
         "answer" : "192.50",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The marked price of an article is 40% above its cost price. If its selling price is 73 1/2% of the marked price, then the percentage profit is:",
         "options" : ["2.9%","2.7%","2.6%","2.5%"],
         "answer" : "2.9%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "Ram bought a cell phone and paid 30% less than its original price. He sold it at 50% profit on the price he had paid. The percentage of profit earned by Ram on the original price was:",
         "options" : ["25%","50%","15%","5%"],
         "answer" : "5%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "On selling a painting at Rs.1,498, the gain is 25% more than the loss incurred on selling it at Rs.1,300. In order to gain 25%, the selling price will be:",
         "options" : ["Rs.1,735","Rs.1,335","Rs.1,755","Rs.1,388"],
         "answer" : "Rs.1,735",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The cost price of milk has increased to ‚Çπ62 from ‚Çπ60. The milkman sold milk at 10% profit earlier. What is his profit% now if he sells milk at the same rate?",
         "options" : ["5.46%","6.54%","6.45%","5.64%"],
         "answer" : "6.45%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A piece of land was sold to a person through two middlemen, each gaining 25%. If the person purchased the land for ‚Çπ6,25,000, the original cost (in) of the land was",
         "options" : ["4,25,000","4,00,000","3,50,000","3,75,000"],
         "answer" : "4,00,000",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A shopkeeper bought articles A and B for a total ‚Çπ2,540. He sold A at a gain of 15% and sold B at a loss of 25%. The selling price of A was ‚Çπ109 more than that of B. His profit or loss percentage in the entire transaction was (rounded off to one decimal place):",
         "options" : ["Loss, 8.3%","Profit, 8.3%","Profit, 9.5%","Loss, 9.5%"],
         "answer" : "Loss, 8.3%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A dealer sells rice at a profit of 15% and uses a weight that is 15% less than the actual weight. Find his percentage gain.",
         "options" : ["26%","53.3%","35.3%","37.5%"],
         "answer" : "35.3%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "Muskan buys two kg of pulses for ‚Çπ400 and sells it for ‚Çπ440. She also uses the weight of 850 gm instead of 1 kg. What is Muskan's actual profit percentage?",
         "options" : ["30%","27%","25 15/17%","29 7/17%"],
         "answer" : "29 7/17%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
         "question" : "A shopkeeper is purchasing goods from a wholesaler. The wholesaler is selling 1265 units of goods to the shopkeeper after gaining the sale price of 165 units of goods. What is the gain percentage of the wholesaler?",
         "options" : ["15%","20%","25%","18%"],
         "answer" : "15%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "Mukesh sells almonds at the cost price but uses a false weight and thus gains a 23% profit. How many grams of almonds is he giving for 3.075 kg?",
         "options" : ["2500","2700","2400","2600"],
         "answer" : "2500",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "If by selling 12 textbooks, a seller earns profit equal to the selling price of 4 textbooks, what is his percentage profit ?",
         "options" : ["25%","50%","16 2/3%","30%"],
         "answer" : "50%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The retail price of a fan is Rs.2,530. If the manufacturer gains 10%, the wholesale dealer gains 15% and the retailer gains 25%, then the cost of the product is:",
         "options" : ["Rs.1,500","Rs.1,800","Rs.1,600","Rs.1,700"],
         "answer" : "Rs.1,600",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "In a grocery shop, Samarth sold 950 g of sugar to a customer in place of 1 kg for ‚Çπ54. The cost price of 1 kg sugar was ‚Çπ36. How much profit (in ‚Çπ) did he earn on selling the sugar?",
         "options" : ["16.2","18.7","20.2","19.8"],
         "answer" : "19.8",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The marked price of a television set is ‚Çπ18,000. A shopkeeper allows a discount of 40% and gets a profit of 10%. What is the cost price of the television set?",
         "options" : ["‚Çπ9,531 5/11","‚Çπ8,181 1/11","‚Çπ7,821 3/11","‚Çπ9,818 2/11"],
         "answer" : "‚Çπ9,818 2/11",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A man earns a profit of 45 percent by selling a bike for a certain price. If he sells that bike at double the price, then what will be the profit percentage?",
         "options" : ["80 %","180 %","90 %","190 %"],
         "answer" : "190 %",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "If two mixers and one T.V cost Rs. 700. While two T.Vs and one mixer cost Rs. 980. The value of one T.V is:",
         "options" : ["Rs.420","Rs.400","Rs.450","Rs.480"],
         "answer" : "Rs.420",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A shopkeeper earns 20% profit on his goods. He lost 20% of his goods during a theft. What is his profit or loss percent ?",
         "options" : ["4% loss","4% gain","6% gain","6% loss"],
         "answer" : "4% loss",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A person sold an article at a loss of 4%. Had he sold it at a gain of 1%, he would have received Rs.42.5 more. To gain 18%, what must be his selling price?",
         "options" : ["Rs.756","Rs.900","Rs.1003","Rs.850"],
         "answer" : "Rs.1003",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A man buys 21 mangoes for a rupee. How many mangoes had he sold for a rupee so that there is a loss of 30 percent ?",
         "options" : ["30","40","35","25"],
         "answer" : "30",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "P sells a toy to Q at a profit of 40 percent and Q sells it to R at a profit of 10 percent. If R pays Rs. 539 for the toy, then what was the cost price of toy for P?",
         "options" : ["Rs. 450","Rs. 300","Rs. 400","Rs. 350"],
         "answer" : "Rs. 350",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A man bought an old printer for Rs.2200 and spent Rs.800 on its repair. He sold it for Rs.3600. Find his profit percentage.",
         "options" : ["30%","20%","15%","25%"],
         "answer" : "20%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A dishonest shopkeeper sells sugar at a rate of Rs.45 per kg. The cost price of the sugar is Rs.40 per kg. Even after doing this, he tries to increase his profit by removing 100 gm from each packet of 1 kg. What is the gain percent of the shopkeeper ?",
         "options" : ["30%","35%","20%","25%"],
         "answer" : "25%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A dishonest shopkeeper pretends to sell his goods at cost price but uses false weights and gain 10%. How much false weight he is using instead 1 kg weight ?",
         "options" : ["909.09 gm","900 gm","920.30 gm","911.12 gm"],
         "answer" : "909.09 gm",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
         "question" : "After selling the article for Rs. 430, a person had a loss of 14%. For earning a gain of 14% how much amount an article will be sold?",
         "options" : ["Rs. 480","Rs. 490","Rs. 570","Rs. 600"],
         "answer" : "Rs. 570",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The marked price of an article is 150 percent of the cost price. If 30 percent discount is given, then what will be the profit percentage?",
         "options" : ["3%","5%","6%","4%"],
         "answer" : "5%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A vendor bought 12 oranges for Rs. 50 and sold them at 12 for Rs. 30. Find the loss percentage.",
         "options" : ["30%","25%","40%","45%"],
         "answer" : "40%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The marked price of a chair is 10 percent more than its cost price. If thechair is sold for Rs.300 after a discountof Rs.140, then what will be the losspercentage?",
         "options" : ["20 %","12.5 %","25 %","17 %"],
         "answer" : "25 %",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "If the selling price of 9 boxes is equal to the cost price of 15 boxes. The gain percent is (Selling price of all boxes is same. Cost price of all boxes is same):",
         "options" : ["(50/3)%","(200/3)%","(100/3)%","(140/3)%"],
         "answer" : "(200/3)%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "Vijay sells bananas at the rate of Rs. 13 per dozen and earns a profit of 30 percent. The cost price of the bananas increases by 10 percent. If the selling price remains the same, then what is his new profit percent?",
         "options" : ["16.66%","18.18%","14.28%","12.5%"],
         "answer" : "18.18%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The difference between cost price and selling price is Rs. 143. If profit percentage is 26 percent, then what is the selling price?",
         "options" : ["Rs. 603","Rs. 676","Rs. 693","Rs. 713"],
         "answer" : "Rs. 693",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "The cost price of 50 articles is same as the selling price of x articles. If there is a profit of 25 percent, then what is the value of x? (Selling price of all articles is same. Cost price of all articles is same)",
         "options" : ["20","40","30","25"],
         "answer" : "40",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "By selling 55 meters of cloth, one gains the selling price of 11 meters. Find the gain percent.",
         "options" : ["33%","15%","25%","23%"],
         "answer" : "25%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A person loses 20 percent on selling 80 pens for Rs. 40. What should be the selling price of 80 pens to earn a profit of 10 percent?",
         "options" : ["Rs.80","Rs.60","Rs.55","Rs.65"],
         "answer" : "Rs.55",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A refrigerator and a washing machine were sold for Rs. 24000 each. If the refrigerator was sold at a gain of 20% and the washing machine at a loss of 20%. What is the overall profit or loss percent in the whole transaction?",
         "options" : ["4% profit","5% profit","4% loss","5% loss"],
         "answer" : "4% loss",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "Shivam purchased two watches, first for Rs. 12000 and the second for Rs. 10000. He sold both the watches, first one at the profit of 10 percent and the second at a loss of 10 percent. What is the overall profit or loss?",
         "options" : ["2.25 percent profit","2.25 percent loss","0.909 percent profit","0.909 percent loss"],
         "answer" : "0.909 percent profit",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A fruit seller sells 2/5th part of fruits at a profit of 10% and remaining at a loss of 5%. If the total profit is Rs.1850, then what is the total cost price of fruits?",
         "options" : ["Rs.198000","Rs.205000","Rs.185000","Rs.176000"],
         "answer" : "Rs.185000",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A person earns a profit of 30 percent by selling an article for Rs. 325. How much percent should he increase his selling price to earn a profit of 40 percent?",
         "options" : ["6.66%","8.25%","7.69%","5.25%"],
         "answer" : "7.69%",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
         "question" : "A shopkeeper sells a book at a loss of 60 percent. Had he sold the book for Rs. 150 more, then he would have suffered a loss of 30 percent. To earn a profit of 20 percent, what should be the selling price of the book?",
         "options" : ["Rs. 650","Rs. 600","Rs. 700","Rs. 550"],
         "answer" : "Rs. 600",
         "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "If 2 times of selling price is equal of 3 times of cost price, then what is the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["4 %","40 %","25 %","50 %"],
             "answer" : "50 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "If 80 percent of total articles are sold at a loss of 25 percent and remaining articles are sold at a profit of 20 percent, then what will be the overall loss percentage?",
             "options" : ["20%","18%","16%","22%"],
             "answer" : "16%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "If 80 percent of total articles are sold at a profit of 25 percent and remaining articles are sold at a loss of 20 percent, then what will be the overall profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["15 %","12.5 %","16 %","20 %"],
             "answer" : "16 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Profit after selling a commodity for Rs. 400 is same as loss after selling it for Rs.300. The cost of the commodity is:",
             "options" : ["Rs.450","Rs.400","Rs.350","Rs.250"],
             "answer" : "Rs.350",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Marked price of a car is Rs. 600000. Rahul buys that car at two successive discounts of 30 percent and 20 percent. If after using the car, he sells the car for Rs. 478000, then what is the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["39.87%","36.85%","33.33%","42.26%"],
             "answer" : "42.26%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "40 percent of selling price of a fan is equal to 4/5 of the cost price of the fan. What is the profit percent?",
             "options" : ["150%","125%","100%","120%"],
             "answer" : "100%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "An article is sold at 5 percent loss. If its cost price is decreased by Rs. 20 and selling price is increased by Rs. 13, then profit of 10 percent is earned on it. What is the original selling price of the article?",
             "options" : ["Rs. 266.66","Rs. 221.66","Rs. 283.33","Rs. 250"],
             "answer" : "Rs. 221.66",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The profit earned by selling a jacket for Rs. 3860 is equal to the loss incurred by selling the same jacket for Rs. 1900. What should be the selling price of the jacket to earn 10 percent profit?",
             "options" : ["Rs.3450","Rs.3168","Rs.3360","Rs.3250"],
             "answer" : "Rs.3168",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The difference between cost price and selling price is Rs.341. If the profit percentage is 22 percent, then what is the selling price?",
             "options" : ["Rs.1972","Rs.1752","Rs.1891","Rs.1858"],
             "answer" : "Rs.1891",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A trader buys two articles for Rs.4000 each article. If he earns a profit of 10 percent on one and losses 30 percent on the other, then what will be his  overall loss percentage?",
             "options" : ["5 %","10 %","20 %","15 %"],
             "answer" : "10 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "By selling 100 notebooks, a shopkeeper gains the selling price of 20 notebooks. What is his gain percentage?",
             "options" : ["62.4%","22.5%","50.4%","25%"],
             "answer" : "25%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A man bought two flats for Rs. 6075000 each. He sold one flat at 10% gain and other at 15% loss. How much percent he gain or lose in the whole?",
             "options" : ["5% loss","5% gain","2.5% loss","3% gain"],
             "answer" : "2.5% loss",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Profit obtained on selling an article for Rs. 600 is equal to the loss incurred on selling the same article for Rs. 400. If selling price is Rs. 750, then what is the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["80 %","50 %","70 %","60 %"],
             "answer" : "50 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Shivam purchased two watches, first for Rs. 12000 and the second for Rs. 16000. He sold both the watches, first one at the profit of 10 percent and the second at a loss of 10 percent. What is the overall profit or loss?",
             "options" : ["Profit = Rs. 600","Profit = Rs. 200","Loss = Rs. 800","Loss = Rs. 400"],
             "answer" : "Loss = Rs. 400",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A person sells wheat at a profit of 25 percent. If he reduces its selling price by Rs. 40, then he suffers a loss of 25 percent. What was the initial selling price of the wheat ?",
             "options" : ["Rs.80","Rs.120","Rs.60","Rs.100"],
             "answer" : "Rs.100",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "Ram purchases two watches for Rs.3,500. By selling one watch at a profit of 25 percent and the other at a loss of 10 ‚Äòpercent he neither earns profit nor suffers loss in the whole transaction. What is the cost price of each watch ?",
             "options" : ["Rs. 1500 and Rs. 2000","Rs. 1500 and Rs. 1720","Rs. 1000 and Rs. 2500","Rs. 1250 and Rs. 2250"],
             "answer" : "Rs. 1000 and Rs. 2500",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "On Selling a book at 8/15 of the marked price there is a loss of 20 percent. What will be the ratio of marked price and cost price of the book?",
             "options" : ["5 : 2","6 : 5","5 : 3","3 : 2"],
             "answer" : "3 : 2",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Vijay sells bananas at the rate of Rs. 14 per dozen and earns a profit of 40 percent. The cost price of bananas increases by 30 percent. If the selling price remains the same, then what is his new profit percent?",
             "options" : ["7.69 %","9.09 %","7.14 %","8.33 %"],
             "answer" : "7.69 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The marked price of an article is 20 percent more than its cost price. What maximum discount percentage can be offered by the shopkeeper to sell his article so that there is no loss?",
             "options" : ["16.66 percentage","12.56 percentage","15.33 percentage","13.33 percentage"],
             "answer" : "16.66 percentage",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A dealer sells two machines at the rate of Rs. 15000 per machine. On one he earns a profit of 20 percent and on the other he loses 40 percent. What is his profit/loss percentage in the whole transaction?",
             "options" : ["20 percent loss","10 percent loss","10 percent profit","20 percent profit"],
             "answer" : "20 percent loss",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A milk merchant buys 30 litres of milk at the rate of Rs. 50 per litre and mixes 20 litres of water in it (water is free of cost). If he sells this mixture at the rate of Rs. 48 per litre, then what is the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["40 %","50 %","66.66 %","60 %"],
             "answer" : "60 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A trader sells an article at 20 percent profit. If he buys it at half of the cost price and sells at the same selling price as before, then what will be the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["240 %","40 %","140 %","60 %"],
             "answer" : "140 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Ritika purchased ùë• kg wheat at Rs.30/kg and sold 8 kg of this at Rs. 'x' per kg and remaining at Rs.45/kg. Overall profit percent earned is 10%, then what quantity of wheat Ritika sold at Rs.45/kg?",
             "options" : ["18 kg","16 kg","10 kg","14 kg"],
             "answer" : "10 kg",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper sells a table at a discount of 20 percent and earns a profit of 30 percent. If he sells the same table at 10 percent discount. then what will be his new profit or loss percent?",
             "options" : ["32.5 percent profit","40.5 percent loss","46.25 percent profit","50.5 percent loss"],
             "answer" : "46.25 percent profit",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "If an article is sold at 9/10th of its usual selling price. 20% profit would be made on it. Find the profit percentage which would have been made on it on selling it at its usual selling price.",
             "options" : ["33.33%","25%","30%","20%"],
             "answer" : "33.33%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "If 60 chairs are bought for Rs.24,560, then how many chairs must be sold for Rs.24,560 to earn a profit of 20 percent?",
             "options" : ["50","40","30","60"],
             "answer" : "50",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The marked price of an article is 150 percent of the cost price. If 20 percent discount is given, then what will be the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["20 %","12.5 %","25 %","10 %"],
             "answer" : "20 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Manoj bought two T.V. for Rs.2,280. He sold one at a loss of 20 percent and other at a profit of 10 percent. If each T.V was sold for the same price, then what is the cost price of the TV which was sold at loss?",
             "options" : ["Rs.1,380","Rs.1,320","Rs.1,050","Rs.1,440"],
             "answer" : "Rs.1,320",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A person buys three spectacles at the rate of Rs.4,000 per spectacles. He sells first spectacles at a profit of 30 percent, sells second spectacles at a loss of 10 percent and sells third spectacles at a loss of 10 percent. What is the total percentage of profit earned in the whole transaction?",
             "options" : ["7.14 percent","2.18 percent","3.33 percent","5.41 percent"],
             "answer" : "3.33 percent",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "On selling a table for Rs. 210 and Rs. 420 there will be loss of l1% and l2% respectively. If l1-l2 = 7, then what is the cost price of table ?",
             "options" : ["Rs. 5,000","Rs. 3,000","Rs. 7,000","Rs. 4,000"],
             "answer" : "Rs. 3,000",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "Rajiv sells a pen at a profit of 5 percent. If he sells the pen for Rs. 36 more, then he earns a profit of 14 percent. What is the cost price of the pen?",
             "options" : ["Rs. 600","Rs. 300","Rs. 500","Rs. 400"],
             "answer" : "Rs. 400",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The marked price of an article is 40 percent more than its cost price. If 20 percent discount is given on the marked price, then what will be the profit percentage ?",
             "options" : ["15 %","12 %","10 %","8 %"],
             "answer" : "12 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "In what ratio tea of Rs.60 per kg should be mixed with tea of Rs.70 per kg so that on selling the mixture at Rs.80 per kg there is a profit of 25 percent?",
             "options" : ["3 : 2","2 : 3","5 : 2","4 : 1"],
             "answer" : "3 : 2",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Shivam purchased two watches, first for Rs. 12000 and the second for Rs. 20,000. He sold both the watches, first one at the profit of 10 percent and the second at a loss of 20 percent. What is the overall profit or loss?",
             "options" : ["Profit = Rs. 2600","Loss = Rs. 2800","Loss = Rs. 2400","Profit = Rs. 2200"],
             "answer" : "Loss = Rs. 2800",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The marked price of a chair is 30 percent more than its cost price. If the chair is sold for Rs. 200 after a discount of Rs. 40, then what will be the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["8.34 percent","7.28 percent","9.66 percent","8.13 percent"],
             "answer" : "8.34 percent",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A merchant marks the price of his article 20 percent above the cost price. If he allows 10 percent discount, then what is the profit or loss percentage?",
             "options" : ["8 percent profit","3.33 percent loss","6 percent loss","5 percent profit"],
             "answer" : "8 percent profit",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A faulty weighing machine reads 1 kg when 900 gm is actually weighted on it. The shopkeeper marked the price of his goods by 10%, but unfortunately he was caught by the metrology department and then they ordered him to repair his weighing machine and gave punishment to sell the goods at a 10% discount on cost price for a month. If each customer is now paying ‚Çπ20 for 1 kg, then before the raid _______ amount they have paid for the same quantity. (Rounded off to two places of decimal)",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ27.16","‚Çπ27.04","‚Çπ28.05","‚Çπ28.15"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ27.16",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A dishonest merchant sells goods at a 12.5% loss on the cost price, but uses 28 g weight instead of 36 g. What is his percentage profit or loss?",
             "options" : ["6.25% loss","12.5% gain","18.75% gain","10.5% loss"],
             "answer" : "12.5% gain",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The price of some wooden furniture increases by 65% when it passes through three hands. If the first and second sellers made a profit of 20% and 25%, respectively, then find the profit percentage of the third seller.",
             "options" : ["10%","12.5%","16%","8%"],
             "answer" : "10%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The cost of a piece of diamond varies with the square of its weight. A diamond of Rs.6,084 value is cut into 3 pieces whose weights are in the ratio 3 : 2 : 1. Find the loss involved in the cutting.",
             "options" : ["Rs.3,768","Rs.3,718","Rs.3,168","Rs.3,518"],
             "answer" : "Rs.3,718",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A dishonest trader says to customers that he sells his goods at a cost price, but he uses a false weight and gains 12.5% as profit. How many grams does he use to weigh 1 kg?",
             "options" : ["900 g","880.5 g","850 g","888.8 g"],
             "answer" : "888.8 g",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper earns 10% on an investment but loses 20% on another investment. If the ratio of the two investments is 2 : 3, then the combined loss percentage is:",
             "options" : ["5.5%","7%","6%","8%"],
             "answer" : "8%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Apples were purchased at 100 for Rs.350 and sold at Rs.48 a dozen. What is the profit or loss percentage?",
             "options" : ["Profit 14 2/7 %","Loss 18 3/5 %","Loss 10%","Profit 12%"],
             "answer" : "Profit 14 2/7 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper has 2220 kg of rice. A part of which he sells at a 20% profit and the rest at a 12% profit. He gains 18% on the whole. The quantity (in kg) sold at a 12% profit is:",
             "options" : ["555","1210","1665","425"],
             "answer" : "555",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Three-fourth of a consignment was sold at a profit of 8% and the rest at a loss of 4%. If there was an overall profit of Rs.600, then find the value of the consignment.",
             "options" : ["Rs.15,000","Rs.6,000","Rs.18,000","Rs.12,000"],
             "answer" : "Rs.12,000",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "Ramesh claims that he is selling onions at Rs.36 per kg, which costs him Rs.40 per kg, but he gives 800 grams instead of 1 kg. Find Ramesh's percentage gain or loss.",
             "options" : ["Gain 13.5%","Loss 13.5%","Loss 12.5%","Gain 12.5%"],
             "answer" : "Gain 12.5%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper advertises for selling clothes at a 7% loss. However, by using a false scale of length 1 metre he actually gains 24%. What will be the actual length he uses instead of 1 metre ?",
             "options" : ["75cm","31cm","76cm","93cm"],
             "answer" : "75cm",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A man sells two cows for Rs.15,640 each, gaining 15% on one and losing 15% on the other. Find his total gain or loss.",
             "options" : ["Rs.720 loss","Rs.360 loss","Rs.720 gain","Rs.360 gain"],
             "answer" : "Rs.720 loss",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A dishonest dealer professes to sell his goods at cost price but uses a false weight and thus gains 15%. For a kilogram, he uses a weight of _________ (rounded off to one digit after decimal).",
             "options" : ["833.3 gm","876.7 gm","869.6 gm","898.33 gm"],
             "answer" : "869.6 gm",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Ramesh purchases a table and a chair for Rs.3,900. He sells the table at a profit of 8% and the chair at a profit of 16%. He earns a profit of Rs.540. What is the difference between the original price of the table and the chair?",
             "options" : ["Rs.2,000","Rs.1,800","Rs.1,900","Rs.1,700"],
             "answer" : "Rs.1,800",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A seller uses faulty weight in place of a 2 kg weight and earns a 25% profit. He claims that he is selling on the cost price in front of the customers but uses a faulty weight. How much error is there in the 2 kg weight to gain 25%?",
             "options" : ["250 g","400 g","500 g","300 g"],
             "answer" : "400 g",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A wrist watch is sold for ‚Çπ1,200 at a profit per cent equal to its cost price. Find the cost price of the wrist watch.",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ 400","‚Çπ 250","‚Çπ 350","‚Çπ 300"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ 300",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "What will be the actual profit percentage (rounded off to nearest integer) after selling an article at a certain price, while there occurs a loss of 45% on selling the article at 3/8 of the selling price ?",
             "options" : ["17 %","37 %","47 %","27 %"],
             "answer" : "47 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper sells his items using a faulty balance which measures 25% less. He then marks up his items 15% above the cost price. If he also gives a discount of 10%, then find his net profit percentage on 1 kg items.",
             "options" : ["32%","41%","44%","38%"],
             "answer" : "38%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The cost price of an article is ‚Çπ1,200. On buying four such articles, the customer gets one for free. If the selling price of each article is ‚Çπ1,800, then determine the net percentage profit earned by the shopkeeper on selling four articles.",
             "options" : ["12%","20%","18%","15%"],
             "answer" : "20%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper gives 20% commission on the retail price of one article and earns 5% profit. If his commission is reduced by 10%, then what is his approximate profit  percentage? (Nearest integral value)",
             "options" : ["18%","10%","15%","8%"],
             "answer" : "18%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper claims to sell his articles at ‚Çπ20 per kg which cost him ‚Çπ23 per kg. But while selling, he uses a false weight and gives only 800 gm instead of 1 kg. What is his profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["8 17/23 %","8 16/23 %","8 14/23 %","8 15/23 %"],
             "answer" : "8 16/23 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Rajkumar decides to sell his watch at a discount of 5%. However, his brother purchases it from him and receives an 8% discount. Rajkumar loses Rs.45 in profit as a result of this. What was the watch's marked price?",
             "options" : ["Rs.1,500","Rs.1,410","Rs.1,430","Rs.1,560"],
             "answer" : "Rs.1,500",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A merchant marks up the price of his goods by 40% more than the cost price. He then sells 1/5th of his goods at a discount of 10%, half of the goods at the marked price and the rest of the goods at a discount of 20%. Find his profit percentage.",
             "options" : ["20.4 %","30.2 %","28.8 %","14.6 %"],
             "answer" : "28.8 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A person sells an article for a loss of 18 percent. If he increases the selling price by ‚Çπ144 and decreases the cost price by 30 percent, then there is profit of 20 percent. What is the original selling price?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ 5068","‚Çπ 6036","‚Çπ 5904","‚Çπ 6124"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ 5904",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "The selling prices of articles A and B are the same. A is sold at a profit of 28 percent and B is sold at a loss of 24 percent. If the total selling price of the both articles is ‚Çπ48640, then what is the cost price of A and B, respectively?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ 26000, ‚Çπ 40000","‚Çπ 24000, ‚Çπ 38000","‚Çπ 17000, ‚Çπ 28000","‚Çπ 19000, ‚Çπ 32000"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ 19000, ‚Çπ 32000",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Raheem sold a crockery set for ‚Çπ1,092 at a profit of 20%. What would have been the actual percentage profit or loss on it, if he sold it for ‚Çπ950 (rounded to two decimal places)?",
             "options" : ["5.40% loss","4.40% loss","5.40% profit","4.40% profit"],
             "answer" : "4.40% profit",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Mukesh sells 80% part of a commodity at a profit of 20% and rest of the part at a loss of 5% and in this way earns a profit of ‚Çπ9,300. What was the cost price of the commodity for Mukesh?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ61,000","‚Çπ62,000","‚Çπ60,000","‚Çπ58,000"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ62,000",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "P buys an article for Rs.280 and sells it to Q at a profit of 25%. Q sells it to R at some profit. R sells it to S for Rs.560 making a profit of 40%. What percentage profit (rounded off to the nearest integer) did Q make?",
             "options" : ["26 %","14 %","32 %","20 %"],
             "answer" : "14 %",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A 15% discount is allowed by a tradesman. How much above the cost price (in percentage) must he mark his goods so as to gain 19% ?",
             "options" : ["32%","40%","35%","47%"],
             "answer" : "40%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A multi-store outlet sold 1375 items in a week earning 25% gain. The gain is also equal to the selling price of ‚ÄòQ‚Äô number of items. What is the value of Q ?",
             "options" : ["250","325","225","275"],
             "answer" : "275",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper purchases supplies from a supplier. The supplier sells 750 units of bags to the shopkeeper after gaining the sale price of 125 units of bags. What is the gain percentage of the supplier?",
             "options" : ["16%","20%","22%","15%"],
             "answer" : "20%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper buys three products a, b, c and sells them at 20%, 30%, 40% profit, respectively. What is the ratio of the selling price of these products, if the ratio of their cost prices is 4 : 3 : 2?",
             "options" : ["34 : 54 : 12","48 : 39 : 28","56 : 26 : 21","24 : 39 : 14"],
             "answer" : "48 : 39 : 28",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The cost price of a table to Ravi, was ‚Çπ1,600. Ravi sold this table at a loss of 10%. What was the price at which Ravi sold the table ?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ1,380","‚Çπ1,520","‚Çπ1,510","‚Çπ1,440"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ1,440",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Ranveer bought a computer paying 25% less than the list price and sold it to his neighbour at a 40% profit on his purchase cost. The profit percentage earned by Rnaveer on the list price of the computer is :",
             "options" : ["10%","7.5%","6.67%","5%"],
             "answer" : "5%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Rohit purchased 12 kg of oranges for a total price of ‚Çπ480 and 18 kg of guavas at ‚Çπ30 per kg. What is the per kg average cost of the fruits purchased by Rohit?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ36.00","‚Çπ34.00","‚Çπ37.20","‚Çπ38.20"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ34.00",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A bought a bag and a bottle for a total of ‚Çπ900. He sold the bottle at a profit of 12% and the bag at a profit of 20%. If he earned a total profit of ‚Çπ160.80, then calculate the cost price of the bottle.",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ320","‚Çπ300","‚Çπ200","‚Çπ240"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ240",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The ratio of the cost price of an item and the profit gained while selling the item is 4 : 1. What is the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["20%","25%","15%","18%"],
             "answer" : "25%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Shubham bought a book from Meesho at ‚Çπ500. Meesho also charged an additional ‚Çπ25 for packaging and ‚Çπ50 for delivering the book. For what amount should Shubham sell his book to make a profit of 16%?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ667","‚Çπ612","‚Çπ783","‚Çπ458"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ667",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "If 25% discount is given on an article, then there will be a loss of 15% . if the article is sold at its marked price, Then what will the profit percentage be? [Give your answer correct to 2 decimal places]",
             "options" : ["15.66%","12.66%","13.33%","10.22%"],
             "answer" : "13.33%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "A person buys some bananas at ‚ÇπY per dozen and sells them at ‚ÇπY/4 per banana. What is his gain percentage?",
             "options" : ["200%","50%","80%","100%"],
             "answer" : "200%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "2/5 of the marked price of an item is equal to 4/7 of its cost price. If a discount of 15% is given on its sale, then what is the approximate profit percentage earned?",
             "options" : ["19.84%","23.63%","21.43%","14.28%"],
             "answer" : "21.43%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A retailer bought 50 kg of Arhar Dal at a discount of 20%. Another 2 kg of Arhar dal was offered to him for free by the wholesaler on the purchase of 50 kg of the dal. If the retailer sells the entire quantity of the dal at the marked price to a customer, what is the profit percentage gained by the retailer?",
             "options" : ["30%","22%","12%","15%"],
             "answer" : "30%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The Cost prices of a pen and a notebook are ‚Çπ600 and ‚Çπ4,000 respectively. If the pen and the notebook are sold at losses of 20% and 32% respectively, what will be the approximate percentage of total loss incurred through the two sales made?",
             "options" : ["21.40%","26.08%","30.43%","28.42%"],
             "answer" : "30.43%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper earns a profit of 16% if he allows a discount of 20% on the marked price of an article. What will be the profit % earned by the shopkeeper if he sold the article at its marked price?",
             "options" : ["45%","35%","36%","55%"],
             "answer" : "45%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The selling price of a desktop is 9 times of the profit earned on selling this desktop. What is the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["10%","12.5%","11.11%","8.33%"],
             "answer" : "12.5%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Nalini purchased 20 dozen apples at ‚Çπ48 per dozen. She sold 8 dozen of them at 10% profit and the remaining 12 dozen at 20% profit. What is the overall profit percentage gained in this transaction?",
             "options" : ["10%","45%","16%","22%"],
             "answer" : "16%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Kapil bought 100 frocks at the rate of ‚Çπ320 per frock. Transport expenditure was ‚Çπ 1000. He paid a tax of ‚Çπ1.50 per frock and the labor fee was ‚Çπ500. What should be the selling price per frock if she wants to make a profit of 10%?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ385.45","‚Çπ370.15","‚Çπ390.80","‚Çπ336.50"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ370.15",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The selling prices of an apple and an orange are Rs 90 and Rs 40, respectively. If the profit percentage gained on the sales of an apple and an orange are 50% and 100%, respectively, then what is the total cost price of an apple and an orange.",
             "options" : ["65","100","85","80"],
             "answer" : "80",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A merchant bought 60 sheep at Rs 120 per sheep. He sold 40 of them at RS 150 each. Another 10 of the sheep died. What should be the selling price of the remaining sheep, If he wants a total profit of RS 800?",
             "options" : ["150","180","250","200"],
             "answer" : "200",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A milkman purchases milk at ‚Çπ ‚Äòa‚Äô per litre and sells it at ‚Çπ 1.5a per litre. Still he mixes 2 litres water with every 9 litres of pure milk. What is his profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["250/3%","328/9%","789/5%","1000/3%"],
             "answer" : "250/3%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Vishal and Param each sold their article at ‚Çπ1,818 but Vishal incurred a loss of 10%, while Param gained by 1%. What is the ratio of the cost price of Vishal‚Äôs article to that of Param‚Äôs article?",
             "options" : ["101 : 90","3 : 4","85 : 89","81 : 75"],
             "answer" : "101 : 90",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Kisna buys a cow for ‚Çπ15,000. After one year, he sells it for ‚Çπ18,500. After one year, again he buys the same cow at ‚Çπ19,000 and sells it for ‚Çπ22,300. What is the overall profit percentage of Kisna?",
             "options" : ["18 %","10%","20%","15%"],
             "answer" : "20%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A mobile phone is sold at a profit of 80%. The nominal profit is approximately what percentage of the selling price of the mobile phone?",
             "options" : ["33.33%","28.56%","44.44%","36.66%"],
             "answer" : "44.44%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "David purchased an item and marked his price up by 10%. He sold the same item by giving a discount of 5% and he made a profit of Rs.12.87. What is the actual cost price of the item?",
             "options" : ["Rs 220","Rs 280","Rs 286","Rs 256"],
             "answer" : "Rs 286",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "What is the profit percentage of a dishonest cloth merchant who uses a scale which measures 16 2/3 % less than what is marked on it, and also sells a price of 10% higher than the cost price?",
             "options" : ["20%","32%","26%","30%"],
             "answer" : "32%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "When a watch is sold at 7/8th of the marked price, there is profit of 25%. At what percentage more than the cost price has the marked price of the watch been fixed?. [Give your answer correct to 2 decimal places]",
             "options" : ["34.46%","42.86%","37.15%","30%"],
             "answer" : "42.86%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper sold 24 shirts, each at a profit of 20% and 16 shirts, each at a profit of 10%. If he had sold all the 40 shirts, each at a profit of 15% , then his overall profit would have been reduced by ‚Çπ36. What is the cost price of each shirt?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ100","‚Çπ220","‚Çπ90","‚Çπ150"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ90",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A man P purchased a land for ‚Çπ4,32,000 on the outskirts of a city. Due to some reason, its value depreciated at 25% per annum and he sold it to Q after 2 years. At this time, the city expanded and new projects of infrastructures started coming up. As a result of the expansion, there was an appreciation of real estate prices at the rate of 50%. What would be the value (in ‚Çπ) of the land after 2 years, from the time Q bought the land from P ?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ5,46,750","‚Çπ5,57,450","‚Çπ5,76,450","‚Çπ6,05,070"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ5,46,750",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Kamal purchases 80 articles for ‚Çπ11,180 and sells them at a loss equal to the selling price of 6 articles. What will be the selling price of 1 article?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ130","‚Çπ120","‚Çπ135","‚Çπ125"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ130",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper normally makes a profit of 20% in a certain transaction; he weighs 900 g instead of 1 kg, due to an issue with the weighing machine. If he charges 10% less than what he normally charges, what is his actual profit or loss percentage?",
             "options" : ["20%","28%","25%","30%"],
             "answer" : "20%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A fruit seller purchased 300 bananas at the rate of ‚Çπ18 per dozen and sold 200 bananas at the rate of ‚Çπ24 per dozen and the remaining bananas at the rate of ‚Çπ21 per dozen. What is his net profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["28%","26%","27%","27 7/9%"],
             "answer" : "27 7/9%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The marked price of 42 items was equal to the cost price of 70 items. The selling price of 25 items was equal to the marked price of 21 items. Calculate the percentage profit or loss from the sale of each item.",
             "options" : ["42% profit","29% profit","29% loss","40% profit"],
             "answer" : "40% profit",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A seller combines 26 kg of rice priced at ‚Çπ20 per kg with 30 kg of rice priced at ‚Çπ36 per kg and sells the mixture for ‚Çπ30 per kg. What is the percentage of profit he makes?",
             "options" : ["8","5","7","3"],
             "answer" : "5",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A merchant gives an additional discount of 10% on the product after an initial discount of 20% on the listed price. He managed to make a 10% profit by selling the product for ‚Çπ54,000. What was the listed price of the product?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ77,500","‚Çπ77,000","‚Çπ75,000","‚Çπ72,500"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ75,000",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "If half of the quantity of sugar in a bag was sold at a profit of 20%, a quarter of the quantity of sugar in the bag was sold at a profit of 16% and the remaining sugar in the bag was sold at a profit of 24%, and the total profit obtained by selling all the sugar in the bag was ‚Çπ90, what was the cost price of the entire quantity of sugar in the bag?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ450","‚Çπ750","‚Çπ500","‚Çπ400"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ450",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A table fan, passing through two hands, is finally sold at a profit of 30% of the original cost price. If the first dealer makes a profit of 25%, then the profit made by the second dealer is:",
             "options" : ["5%","10%","15%","4%"],
             "answer" : "4%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The marked price of an article is ‚Çπ10,927. Due to the festive season, a certain percentage of discount is declared. Raju buys an article at a reduced price and sells it at ‚Çπ10,927, and makes a profit of 11.5%. What was the percentage discount offered?",
             "options" : ["10.3%","11.3%","11.5%","10.9%"],
             "answer" : "10.3%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A person sold an article at a loss of 18%. Had it been sold for Rs. 960 more, he would have gained 12%. If the article is sold for Rs. 3,840, then how much is the profit percentage?",
             "options" : ["15%","24%","20%","21%"],
             "answer" : "20%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The cost price of two articles A and B are in the ratio 4 : 5 . While selling these articles ,the shopkeepers gains 10% on article A and 20% on article B and the difference in their selling price is ‚Çπ480. The difference in the cost price (in ‚Çπ) of article B and A is ;",
             "options" : ["250","300","400","350"],
             "answer" : "300",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper bought 40 pieces of an article at a rate of ‚Çπ50 per item.He sold 35 pieces with 20% profit. The remaining 5 Pieces were found to be damaged and he sold them with 10% loss. Find his overall profit percentage.",
             "options" : ["30%","32.5%","16.25%","10%"],
             "answer" : "16.25%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Manjeet bought a second hand motorbike for ‡§∞22,000 and spent ‡§∞3,000 on its overhauling and maintenance . He then sold it with 12% profit.If he had sold it for ‡§∞500 less, then what would have been his profit percentage ?",
             "options" : ["10.5%","10%","5%","8%"],
             "answer" : "10%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "An article is sold at a certain price. If it is sold at 70% of this price, then there is a loss of 10%. What is the percentage profit, when it is sold at the original selling price ?",
             "options" : ["50/7%","200/7%","300/7%","100/7%"],
             "answer" : "200/7%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A vegetable vendor sold 1 kg of potatoes for Rs. 25 and earned 25% profit. In the evening, he started selling potatoes with only 10% profit. At what cost (in ‚Çπ) per kg did he sell the potatoes in the evening?",
             "options" : ["21","20","24","22"],
             "answer" : "22",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "An article is sold at a certainprice. If it is sold at 33 1/3% of this price,  there is a loss of 33 1/3%. What is the  percentage profit if the article is sold at 80% of its original selling price?",
             "options" : ["70%","60%","40%","50%"],
             "answer" : "60%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Some fruits are bought at 11 for ‚Çπ100 and twice the number at 8 for ‚Çπ100. If all the fruits are sold at 9 for ‚Çπ100, then what is the profit or loss percentage?",
             "options" : ["Gain, 3%","Loss, 3%","Gain, 4 1/9%","Loss, 2 2/9%"],
             "answer" : "Loss, 2 2/9%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The cost prices of two articles are in the ratio 4 : 5. While selling these articles, the shopkeeper gains 10% on one article and 20% profit on the other article, and the difference in the selling price is ‚Çπ480. Find the total cost price of both the articles.",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ3,000","‚Çπ2,700","‚Çπ2,500","‚Çπ2,800"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ2,700",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "When an article is sold for ‚Çπ768, the profit percentage is x%. When the same article is sold for ‚Çπ896, the profit percentage is (x + 20)%. What is the value of x?",
             "options" : ["30","25","15","20"],
             "answer" : "20",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The cost price of 30 articles is the same as the selling price of x articles. If the profit is 25%, then the value of x is:",
             "options" : ["18","30","24","25"],
             "answer" : "24",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A man sold a radio and a TV set together for ‚Çπ30,400, thereby making a profit of 25% on the radio and 10% on the TV set. By selling them together for ‚Çπ30,700, he would have made a 10% profit on the radio and 25% on the TV set. The cost price of the radio is:",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ10,000","‚Çπ12,000","‚Çπ8,000","‚Çπ9,000"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ12,000",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper bought 500 notebooks. He sold 300 of them for the price he paid for all 500 notebooks. He sold 140 notebooks at a 20% higher rate than that at which he sold 300 notebooks and the remaining at the cost price.What is the profit percentage in the whole transaction?",
             "options" : ["60%","56%","68%","64%"],
             "answer" : "68%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A trader purchased 500 kg of sugar at ‚Çπ40 per kg. He sold 200 kg of it at a profit of 10% and 120 kg at a loss of 5%. At what rate per kg (in ‚Çπ, correct to 2 decimal places) should he sell the remaining sugar to gain 12% on his initial investment?",
             "options" : ["48.67","52.33","50.22","44.80"],
             "answer" : "50.22",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Raghu bought an article for ‚Çπ6,800 and spent ‚Çπ700 on its repairs. He marked this article at 8% above the overall cost price. He sold the article for ‚Çπ6,480 after giving x% discount. The value of x is:",
             "options" : ["15%","25%","18%","20%"],
             "answer" : "20%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The marked price of an article is 35% above its cost price. After giving a 20% discount on the marked price, it is sold for ‚Çπ432. What is the cost price of the article?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ400","‚Çπ380","‚Çπ425","‚Çπ420"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ400",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper buys 60 oranges at 10 for ‚Çπ72, and an equal number at 12 for ‚Çπ90. He spends ‚Çπ118 on the transaction and sells all the oranges that he buys. If there is a profit of 26% in the entire transaction, then what is the selling price of 32 oranges?",
             "options" : ["‚Çπ336","‚Çπ313.60","‚Çπ316.80","‚Çπ320"],
             "answer" : "‚Çπ336",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
             "question" : "If a shopkeeper purchases a certain number of items for a certain sum and sells a fraction of the said number for the same amount, then his profit is 300%. What is the fraction?",
             "options" : ["1/4","1/3","1/6","1/2"],
             "answer" : "1/4",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper bought 20 kg of sugar at Rs.45 per kg, 25 kg of sugar at Rs.50 per kg and 35 kg of sugar at Rs.40 per kg. He spent a sum of Rs.450 on transportation and other expenses. He mixed all the three types of sugar and sold all the stock at Rs.52.50 per kg. His profit percent in the entire transaction is:",
             "options" : ["5%","7.25%","4.25%","6.5%"],
             "answer" : "5%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper sold two items. The selling price of the first item equals the cost price of the second item. He sold the first item at a profit of 20%, and the second item at a loss of 10%. What is the overall profit/loss percent?",
             "options" : ["Loss, 4 6/11%","Profit, 3 7/11%","Profit, 4 7/11%","Loss, 8 1/3%"],
             "answer" : "Profit, 3 7/11%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper sold an article at four-fifth of the marked price and suffered a loss of 3 1/3%. Find the profit percent, if he sold the article at the marked price. (correct to nearest integer)",
             "options" : ["20","22","18","21"],
             "answer" : "21",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A shopkeeper bought 40 dozen eggs at Rs. 1.40 each. 80 eggs were broken in transportation. He sold the remaining eggs at Rs. 1.60 each. What is his profit or loss per cent?",
             "options" : ["Loss, 3 19/27","Profit, 3 19/27","Profit, 4 16/21","Loss, 4 16/21"],
             "answer" : "Profit, 4 16/21",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A man buys goods for Rs.8000. He sells 30% of those goods at a profit of 12% and 40% of the remaining goods at a profit of 25%. At what profit percentage should he sell the remaining goods to gain 30% in the entire transaction. (correct to one decimal place)?",
             "options" : ["42.6%","46.2%","48.4%","31.6%"],
             "answer" : "46.2%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "By selling a car for Rs.6,32,500, a showroom owner makes a profit of 15%. If he sold the car at Rs. 8,10,000, then what would be the profit percentage (correct to one decimal place)",
             "options" : ["47.3%","44.8%","41.5%","51.4%"],
             "answer" : "47.3%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A person sold an article at a loss of 16%. Had he sold it for Rs. 660 more, he would have gained 8%. If the article is sold at Rs. 3,080, then how much profit percentage is gained?",
             "options" : ["10%","15%","20%","12%"],
             "answer" : "12%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Remi earns a profit of 20% on selling an article of a certain price. If she sells the article for Rs. 8 more, she will gain 30%.What is the original price of 16 such articles ?",
             "options" : ["Rs1,280","Rs1,152","Rs1,120","Rs1,200"],
             "answer" : "Rs1,280",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Anil bought two articles A and B at a total cost of ùëÖùë†10,000. He sold the article A at 15% profit and the article B at 10% loss. In the whole deal, he made no profit or no loss. Find the selling price of the article A.",
             "options" : ["5400","4500","4600","4200"],
             "answer" : "4600",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The difference between the selling prices of some articles if sold for Rs 12 per article instead of Rs 9 per article is Rs 150. If the cost price of these articles is Rs250, then find the selling price of 21 articles if profit earned is 20%.",
             "options" : ["126","136","125","130"],
             "answer" : "126",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "On selling 26 balls for Rs.1350, there is a loss equal to the cost price of eight balls. The cost price of a ball is:",
             "options" : ["70","65","60","75"],
             "answer" : "75",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "A person purchased 40 items at some price. He sold some items at a profit of 30% by selling them at a price equal to the cost price of 26 items. The remaining items are sold at 18% profit. The total profit percentage is:",
             "options" : ["27%","28%","25%","24%"],
             "answer" : "24%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "The selling price of a book, including the sales tax, is Rs 956.34. The rate of sales tax is 10%. If the shopkeeper has made a profit of 15%, then the cost price of the book is:",
             "options" : ["Rs 756","Rs 797.34","Rs.845.98","Rs.836"],
             "answer" : "Rs 756",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        },
        {
             "question" : "Anu fixes the selling price of an article at 25% above its cost of production. If the cost of production goes up by 20% and she raises the selling price by 10%, then her percentage profit is (correct to one decimal place):",
             "options" : ["16.4%","14.6%","13.8%","15.2%"],
             "answer" : "14.6%",
             "category" : "Profit and Loss"
        }
    ]    
]